Which plan is better in 2026 HDFC Urbos
Optima Secure Plus Plan ICICI
Lobbard's Elovate Plan and Star Health's
Superstar Plan with the Secure variant that is what we are
going to understand
in this video Mahavir [Music] Chopra The
Founder and Chief Executive Officer of
Beshaq.org
[Music]
Now here what we will be covering in this
video number one a comparison of the unique
features with the Finant two a quick roll call
of all the core benefits and waiting
periods and the Finant.  Third, a detailed look
at the real-world service experience,
starting with customer service and
mostly claims experience.  Let's give a
quick comparison of pricing and finally we
will understand how these plans are
rated by ILM Research.  India's only
independent insurance research platform
that through deep research gives one single data
back rating for all insurance plans.
Making it easier to compare all products
in the market.  Starting with the USP.  The
first USP of HDFC Arbo is called the
Secure Benefit.  In this you basically
get 2x cover from day one.  So if your
cover is Rs 10 lakh, your cover becomes Rs 20 lakh from the first day.
This is basically a buy one get one
free theme where your cover is
doubled from day one.
What is the USB of ICI Lobard Elvet?  That is what we are
going to understand.  The first USP is that they have
some insured options.  Which has an
additional sum insured option.  Which is the
Unlimited Sum Insured option.  Like you
get sum insured option of 5 lakh, 10
lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh whatever the options are.  So
in the dropdown you are
also given the option of unlimited sum insured.  ICICI
Elevate.  Now the other USP of ICICI Elevate is
also a very unique feature that this company
is bringing out.  It's called the World
Wide Cover.  It is an add on that is
available in this plan.  Basically, all the
health insurance plans available in India
typically
cover only the hospitalization that takes place in India.  If you need to
cover outside hospitalization, you will have to
take add-ons for that.  ICICI
Alamard gives a very very good add on
called the World Wide Cover add on.  It
covers both emergency and plant treatments.
In this, basically your cover is the same as the
typical sum insured cover.  The
maximum amount is Rs 3 crore.
So, if you have a cover of Rs 5 crore
or unlimited cover, then your
worldwide cover will be capped at Rs 3 crore.  The
waiting period in this is basically 2 years
except for accidental
emergencies and if you want to reduce the waiting period from 2 years to one
year then by paying an add on
you can convert two years into one year by paying a little money.  The
thing to understand is that
this plan offers only cashless
treatment.  Meaning, you will feel positive that
wow, it is very good that you will not
get it cashless.  But there is a negative factor in this that
if you go to a non-network hospital
outside, if you are in any country and
you have to go to a hospital which is non-
network, then you may not get coverage.
So this is a very important thing to understand because it is an
emergency treatment.  You may not
find a hospital that is in network and
end up having to pay from your pocket.  That's very
important to understand.  Now moving on to
the USP that stars help superstars.  This
brand called Secure Bearings.  The first
is called the Freeze Your Age benefit.  Freezing
your age means that insurance
companies typically increase your premium every year
depending on your age.
What this feature offers you is that basically,
if you enter this plan, let's say at the age
of 30 and you continue this plan, you can
renew this plan without making any
claim.  Whether your age is 31, 35, 40 or 45,
you will
pay the same premium for the plan as that of a 30 year old.  This
is a very good feature because there are
many customers who tell us
that I did not make a claim, then
why did my premium increase?  So that is the answer to this question that this is a
plan which
offers you a coverage with the premium that is
stuck to the age when you enter the plan.  This
feature is applicable only till 55 years of age.
After 56 years, basically
your premium will be linked to your age.   The thing
to understand is if you make a claim in this
period, you
took the plan at the age of 30 and if you make a
claim at the age of 40, after that the premium for
40 years has to be paid at the age of 40 and for 41 years at the age of 41, so
this benefit is
available when you do not make a claim and
up to 55 years, it is a good feature because a lot of
people do not want to pay premiums
if we have not made a claim, next is
called the unlimited sum insured for one or
two claims, now this is becoming a very common
feature with all the new comprehensive
plans that are getting
introduced, in this it happens that
typically when we buy help insurance, we
choose a sum insured, right, this
sum insured is done on the
basis of a calculation that okay, this much
sum insured, so  It will be enough.  But there is
always this view in the back of our mind
that what if this sum insured
is not enough for a particular claim that happens
in the lifetime.  This is the answer to that question that
most insurance companies recently are now
introducing this feature where
one claim in your lifetime you will be
able to make without any sum insured limit.   So, it
means if you took a cover of Rs 10 lakh, you
took a cover of Rs 15 lakh, you took a cover of Rs 20 lakh.
But whatever your claim is, be it 1 crore, 2
crore, 5 crore, 10 crore, the
insurance company is not going to put any
limits, you can claim up to whatever is
your hospital bill without having to worry about
the sum insured.  This is a great feature:
All the three insurance companies and
insurance plans that we are discussing
today are offering this.  Let me look at if there are any
specific limitations and
benefits that each of these offers.  HDFC Ergo has
an additional benefit that if you
take a sum insured of more than Rs 50 lakh,
you can use it twice, not just once.  There
is a condition in ICIC that I am
going to read out quickly.  It says that add-ons
must be opted in only within the first
two years.  In the case of Star Health, it says add-ons must be
opted in for the first three
years.  So obviously, you should opt for this plan
within one, two or three years of purchasing it.
After that, this feature may
not be available to you.  Next we
compare the bonuses in all these three
plans.  Now interestingly all these three
companies are offering a loyalty bonus.  This means that the
bonus you are getting will not be linked to the claim.
This is not a no claim bonus.
This is a loyalty bonus and a guaranteed bonus.
Let's understand what these three
plans are offering.  So HDFC Organo calls
this the infinite benefit.  It is not an
add on.  It is basically included as a
part of Optima Secure Plus.  It
basically gives you a guaranteed bonus of 100%
for every year you renew.  Even
more interesting is that there is
no cap on the accumulation.  This means that for every
year you keep renewing,
your sum insured will keep increasing by 100% every year
for your lifetime.  Which
is an interesting and a very big
benefit that the insurance company is offering.
Now Let's Look at How ICICI LBA
Offers Elevate?  He is providing this through this add on.
It's called the Power Booster add on.
If you don't take the add on then the regular
bonus is 20% every year up to 100%
capping.  If you take this add-on, you will
get a guaranteed bonus.  You will also get 100% every year.
And again in this case also there is
no cap on bonus accumulation.  Very
similar to HDFC Argos Optima Secure
Plus is what is being offered as ICIB but with
the option of taking an ad of only through the
ad of Now Superstar Secure brand which is
of Star, let us understand how it is given in it.
Guaranteed bonus increases by
100% of the SI every year again. No cap on
accumulation.  Brilliant so all the three
companies are offering the same thing.  Only ICI
Amma is offering it to the add on.
Otherwise all these three companies are giving you
bonus unlimited 100% every.  One Thing Before
We Move Ahead in the video.  Look, health
insurance is full of terms and conditions,
legal and medical.  Well I try to keep it easy
for you to understand at any
point in time if you are feeling confused
and want to have a personalized one to one
conversation with industry experts.  You
can always consult India's top 5%
insurance experts only on course.  For
completely completely free.  Mind you, these are
not call center freshers but real
experts with real experience.  So now let's
understand the core benefits.
What are core benefits?  Which basically accounts for
most of your hospital bill.
Ok?  So
listen carefully.  Room rent limit is a very
important part.  This results in significant
deductions.  So let's
understand how these plans are covering the
room rent limit.  HDFC Urbo Optima
Secure Plus has no room rent and room
capping.  Basically that means you
can get any type of room.  There will be
no deduction of any kind.  You can take any type of room.
Star Health Superstar's
plan, this plan named Secure,
also does not have any limit.
By default, you
get a single private AC room at ICICI LBA Elevate.  You will get the cheapest
private AC room in the hospital.
If you want to convert it into any room,
you can do so through an add-on.  The
cost of this add-on is not very high.  The
last time we checked, for a sum insured of Rs 10 lakh,
if you take the add-on, if you are
taking a 30 year old family member, then it comes to
Rs 600-700.  Now let's compare pre and
post hospitalization expenses.
60 Days Free & 180 Days
Post in case of HDFCO Optima Secure
Plus.  ICICI Alamard Elevate which is 90 days
free and 180 days post and 90 days free
and 180 days post similar to Star
Health Superstar Secure Plan.  Day care
treatments, modern treatments and organ
donors are all covered without any
limitations and without any restrictive
list.  So,
this is basically a signal for all comprehensive plans whether it is a
comprehensive plan or not.  All the
three plans are comprehensive plans.  Now,
moving on to temporary explosions,
waiting periods of all the three plans,
very very important.  Your plan doesn't start
all of your coverage from day one when you buy it.
Gradually as you
basically keep paying premiums over the years
your coverage basically opens up and that's what we are
going to understand.  Initial
Waiting Period: When you buy the policy in the first year, there is a
waiting
period of 30 days.  There is a standard waiting period
for all insurance plans in the
country.  Health Insurance Plans in the
Country.  Hospitalization claims for sickness and diseases in the first 30 days are
not covered.  Only accident is covered.
After that waiting periods after that
sorry not waiting period after that you can make
sickness claims.  The second
waiting period is the waiting period for specified diseases.
It basically consists of a list.  The
names of illnesses, diseases or treatments mentioned in that list are
not usually covered as a standard for 2 years.  Which
is cataract, piles, slip disc, kidney
stone.  There is
a list of many such typical diseases and
they are not covered for two years.  That is what is
typically the case with all
standard plans.  In these three plants.
HDFC ICICI Elevate and Star Health Ah that
24 months is there.  There is in ICI Lum
Elevate an additional waiting period of 90 days
for non-PD blood pressure, diabetes and
cardiac conditions.  What that means is that
diabetes, blood pressure and cardiac
conditions are not included in the two-year waiting period.  He has other diseases.
But in this, if you take ICI Embard Alveda
plan, then apart from the 30 days
waiting period for sickness which I had told
you, if these three things are
related to blood pressure, diabetes
or cardiac condition,
in the first year, if you make a claim within 90 days, then the
waiting period will be applicable.  You
cannot claim.  Now let's look at if there are any
modifications that any of these
three plans offer in case of specified
disease waiting period.  So, ICICI has
a modification available in its Elevate plan
for the two year waiting period which
reduces the waiting period to 12 months.   If
you pay extra premium, your
waiting period will increase from two years to one year
for this list of illnesses and
diseases and treatments.  Now let us understand the
waiting period of pre-existing diseases.
So as a standard practice
all insurance companies have a three year
waiting period as per the IDI definition.   Let us
understand how these plans are
offering waiting periods for pre-
existing diseases.  All three plans have a
standard waiting period of 36 months.   Let us
understand the modifications.  The first
modification is available in the Elevate plan with ICICI
Low LBA.  Where
you can convert those 36 months that I told
you into 24 months or 12 months.
Paying Premium by Basic by Paying
Premium.  Alright you have to take an add on.
And you have to pay additional premium by
which you can reduce the waiting period for
your pre-existing disease from three
years to two years and one year.  Now there is one
more modification that is available in all the
three insurance plans that we are talking
about.  These are completing insurance
companies.  These people compete very harshly
with each other.  So you
will see that many features are matching
here.  HDFCO Oct Cure PS has
ABCD Chronic Care Rider in which you can
cover Asthma, Blood Pressure, Cholesterol and Diabetes within 30 days.
Basically you have to apply.  You have to
pay an additional premium and
accordingly, these four
diseases that I mentioned will be covered for 31 days.  ICI lumps up
the game by basically covering six
instances of the four diseases.  It says that A
B CD will definitely cover asthma, blood pressure,
cholesterol, diabetes.
Apart from that, obesity can also be covered
from 31 days.  And angioplasty if there is a
gap of one year from your buying the policy can also be
covered by paying additional
premium and getting your waiting period
reduced from three years to 30 days
not even one year.  Now Star Health
Superstar Secure is
situated between HDFC Bank and ICICI Bank. It says that it
covers five
illnesses by 30-31 day.  This means that
after a waiting period of 30 days, five illnesses will be
covered.  Esma blood pressure
cholesterol diabetes is common in all the
three companies.  A coronary artery disease
angioplasty with a gap of one year is also
covered in Star Health Superstar with
the secure brand Basically ICICI
Lombard is covering obesity and angioplasty as an
additional over ABCD and
Star Health Superstar plan is
basically covering angioplasty as an
additional over ABCD that is how we have
compared all the temporary exclusions now we are
moving to customer service there is no such
standard metric of customer service
disclosed ILM Research is they do their
own research to find out how the
customer service operates over toll free
numbers and Twitter responses.
How does she respond on Twitter?
How does it respond to toll free calls?   Does the
insurance company pick up the phone or not
?  That is what we understand.  HDFC
and Go have been marked as slow for toll
free.  ICIC LAD is also Mark S. Slow.
Meaning, if you are trying to pay toll free then
you will face problems.
You will not get a response so easily.  Star Health has been
marked as quick.  Meaning you will
get a quick response.  Chances are high.
Depending on the audits that are based on the
audits that have been conducted by IM Research.
Response time on average for HDFC is slow
for ICICI as well as on average in case of
star.  The star is not responding promptly on Twitter.  It is
responding very slowly.
But if you call,
you will get a fast response as per our audit.
Now Moving On To Claims Experience.
Very important because no matter how good a product we
buy, what do we ultimately want?
Claim that is what we are going to
understand for the parameters that we are
going to compare.  First is the speed of
claim settlement.  How many
claims does an insurance
company settle in the first 30 days?  It shows
what is the speed of the insurance company?  Claim settlement.
HDFC ARO speed is 96.63%.  So
if 100 claims come, then 96.63% claims are
settled within the first 30 days.  Quite a
good number.  ICICI is even better at 99.94%, meaning out of
100 claims, 99.94% were settled
in the first 30 days.  Then Star Health
97.69% means everyone is very close but the
best among them is ICICI Long Bad.
Next is Star Health in terms of
speed and then it is HDFCO claim complaint
meaning complaints kitne aate hain on claims
registered with the insurance company is what we are
going to understand.  0.15% in
case of HDFC Akor 0.14% in case of ICICI
LMA Very Very Close.  0.52% in case of
Star Health means almost three times more
than HDFCO and ICICI along with so
Star Health is not doing that well in claim complaints.
Ah Incurred Claim Ratio What it is
Incurred Claim Ratio Incurred
Claim Ratio is basically if you are
a person company collects ₹100 then
what percentage of the premium
collected goes into claim.  What do we
learn from this?  How much money is an individual company
collecting?  How much of that
premium is she paying for the claim.
Right?  Normally, we have a
threshold or a thumb rule that we
say that 60 to 80% is a good ratio. If a
company is basically less than 60%, it means
it is rejecting a lot of claims
and if it is above 80%, then basically the premium is
not good, it is not viable for
that company and the insurance company will
increase the premium in future. If it is between 60 and 80, then
we are safe, the customer is safe.
Let's look at what is the ratio for each of
these companies. 87.04% in the case of HDFC Eggo. So, the
premium incurred claim ratio of HDFCO is
higher than the threshold we spoke about, so there are
chances of their premium increasing as per
our theory. 85.53% in the case of ICICI, this is also crossing 80%.
This means that the
premium of ICICI Low LBA is also
very high in comparison to the claims.
70.53% in case of Star Health they are
falling in the ratio.  So it's a good thing
it's a green flag for Star Health.   Let us
understand the claim rejection ratio.
What is claim rejection ratio?  All the
claims that an insurance company receives.
How many of those claims have been rejected?
This is what we have to understand.  We have to understand
whether an insurance company pays the claim
or not.  How much does she reject?   That is what we are
going to understand.
HDFC Argos Claim Rejection Ratio is
2.47% One of the best that I have seen so
far and all the reviews that I have done.
ICICI rejection ratio is 14.11% quite
high almost one of the highest that I have seen
so far and starts is
11.32% which is also very-very high.  So
in rejection ratio HDFC Eggo is fairing really really well
as compared to these two
companies.  Which is something that you should note
for.  Now moving on to pricing.
Understanding pricing is also equivalent
obviously because our claim performance should also be
good.  Your product is also good,
core benefits are also good.  The US pieces are very
good.  But the premium should be affordable.
So standard Mr. Kumar 30 year
old covering himself.  His wife who is also
30 years old.  What is the premium for a kid who is one year old
living in Mumbai for Rs 10 lakh
?  Quickly understand.  2243
in case of HDFC Optima Secure Plus
13,964
in case of ICICI LBA Elevate 18,970 in case
of Star Health Superstar.  So there
is a huge difference in premiums.  Right?  Almost
ICICS premium is half of almost half of
HDFC premium.  One thing that you need to
understand is that HDFC has
OnePlus One offer for you.  The sum insured of Rs 10 lakh that I have taken is now the
sum insured of Rs 20 lakh from the first day.  You are getting a cover of Rs 20 lakh.
That's a huge difference.  ICICI
LBA Elevate needs to understand everything
it offers.
ICICI LBA is offering all the benefits through add-ons only.
You have to add one thing at each place
which is not added in premium.
Right?  From that perspective, you have to
understand that it's a bare
minimum flat product, and then you have to add
things on it to be able to basically make it
customized to what you need, but at that
level, it's the cheapest and most affordable
plan of all the three plans that we have
compared. Star Health is in the middle. Star
Health is basically offering something which is like
an average premium that typically, and
insurance companies would charge for a 10 lakh
time. Okay, now we are going to basically
understand the ratings of these three
plans. It's very important to understand the
ratings because there are so many
features, so many benefits, ah,
terms and conditions that we have seen, there are
waiting periods. Understanding all of them,
combining them, see which plan should be
taken and which plan should not be taken. Where does which plan
stand? It's very difficult to combine the claims matrix, the
service matrix,
so there should be a
parameter.  This is what ILM Research
solves. ILM Research is India's
only independent insurance research
platform that basically does not take any
kind of marketing, advertising, affiliate
money from any insurance company, that is,
insurers, that is 100% unbiased,
uninfluenced by any insurance
company, that helps it give you the
ratings that you want, you need to decide on
insurance plans.  So let us understand
what are ratings?  The first rating is the
rating of product benefits, that is,
if we put all the products in the market together and
see which is the best product, then
it will get a rating of five and relatively all
other companies will get a rating.  Where each
of these three plans fall is what we are
going to understand.  HDFCO Optimizer
Plus gets a 4.9 rating out of five
which is basically closest to five.
Which typically basically means that it is
offering you all the best features that are
important for you from a point of view
of covering hospitalization expenses.
4.37 In case of ICIC lump not bad.
ICICI Lamb Elevate Market 4.37.  Star
Health Superstar The Secure V has market cap of
4.89 so close to HDFC Argos Opt
Secure Plus.  So what do you
call it very very?  It is a tough fight on
product benefits of all these three
plans.  Not bad each of these companies are
doing very well in offering product
benefits.  How are the ratings at Let's Look At Customer Service
?  3.29 In case of HDFC
Ergo Not Good.  HDFC Not basically s on The
Research That Has Been Carried Out The Study That Has
Been Carried Out by ILM.  The customer
service is not good about HDFC Orgango.
4.24 In case of ICIL 2.2 In case of Starl
Very Very Poor.  That basically means that
if you want to talk to Starrel on the phone or
you need any service from Starrel, then there can be a
lot of problems.  2.2 is very very bad
, very very visible.  Ah Claims
Experience, The Most Important Thing That All
of Us Want to Understand.  Let's understand its rating.
4.98 in case of HDFCO, 3.84 in
case of ICIC, 3.69 in case of Star Health.
So, 4.98 is a near five rating which
basically means that when we or ILM did
all this research ratings, the
closest to the best is what HDFCO
gets in claims performance.  Commendable
performance by HDFCO claims side.  Overall
Rating Let us understand what is Overall Rating
?  The overall rating is of HDFC Organo Optima
Secure Plus.  Now that
we've looked at these claims, what is a
blended rating by IM, combining customer service and product benefits
?  4.41 in case of HDFCO
Optima Secure Plus with ICICI along with Elevate
4.1 Star Health Superstar Secure at
3.37.  So basically if you are looking at these
three plans and you are Mr. Kumar the
person that we were talking about then HDFC
Optima Secure Plus falls to be the best
plan among these three plans.  But very very
important to understand that this is
based on these ratings are based on a
specific person, a standard person, someone who we
look at an issue, basically looks at it
from a point of view, specifically
from a particular city, particular needs, right,
but you may have your own needs, you may have your
own preference, you may have your own
hospitals that you want to be covered under
your network, you will be belonging to a
specific city, you may have your own budgets,
preferences, all that from that point of view, if
you are looking at actually buying any of
these plans, before you do you make any decision, you should always talk
to a good insurance
expert, someone who has the experience and
the track record of helping people with
claims.  If there is anyone in your circle who is
known for help insurance then you should talk
to them.  Try to basically
understand the plan from them and then buy from
them.  If you do not have some good kind
of expert in your area, your
circle, your location, and you are looking for a
really good, solid insurance expert,
you can always come to Of course.  Org and
consult insurance experts on our
platform.  These are people, who have minimum
three years of experience up to 20 years
of experience.  The average experience is
around 9.5 years of all the experts
that are there on a platform.  They are
rigorously tested screens.  They have exams.
They have two interviews.
After that these are listed on our panel.
You can consult these people for free on
a platform and get to know which is the
plan that is best suited for your
specific needs.  If there is any
specific question that I have not been able
to answer with in this specific video
that we have created.  Anything that you want
to ask.  Any feedback you want to give on the
kind of comparison that we do.  BR Guest
Come in the Comment Section Ask the Question.
Leave your feedback.  We are more than happy to
learn from you, answer your questions.  And
let's participate together to basically
help others also answer their questions if they have any.
And If You Found The Video
Helpful, Do Click The Like Button.  It does
encourage us to do more such videos.  More true
comparisons.  It helps us it takes a lot of
effort not only from me but from the entire
team who is doing these videos
ensuring that you get the right information
before you make decisions.  So before you go do
press the like button we would be very-very
happy.  And very very important if you are
looking at buying health insurance and you
are in the journey of considering buying a
health insurance you want to learn more
about health insurance do click on the
subscribe button subscribe to us and
basically we will ensure that you are basically
delivered one of the best content in
insurance in the YouTube space.